City of Houston Collection, 1891-1900
University of Houston Libraries
City of Houston Collection 1891-1900
The City of Houston Collection consists of official correspondence and documents relating to the City of Houston from 1881-1900.
1999-001
1 box, 19 items
Special Collections, University of Houston Libraries
City of Houston
Scope and Contents
The City of Houston Collection consists of official correspondence and documents relating to the City of Houston around the turn of the century. Most of the items relate to physical improvements such as paving being made to the city by the City Engineers Office, and the documents date from 1881-1900. The collection comprises 1 manuscripts box with 19 individual items.
The collection is divided alphabetically according to the office of issue, and then filed chronologically. The Executive Department and Brashear & Dannenbaum, Attorneys at Law have been included in the Mayor's Office series, as they were issued by S.H. Brashear during his term as Mayor.
Index Terms
Terms are either Library of Congress Subject Headings or taken from local sources.
Subjects
Houston (Tex.) Politics and government.; Houston (Tex.) History.
Formats
Correspondence
Acquisition
The collection was given to the University of Houston Libraries by Mrs. Henry (Grace) David.
Access Restrictions
Open for research.
Detailed Description
- City Attorney's Office
  - ALS. Stewart, Jno. S. to Miller, I. Austin., Feb. 14, 1900 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- City Engineer's Office
  - Estimates., Oct. 9, 1891 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Estimates for paving Main St., Dec. 28, 1894 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Memo: Widths of roadway on Washington St., undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Ordinances: Fire Escapes., undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Plans and Specs. For the grading, paving, and construction..., undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
- City Secretary's Office
  - ALS. Richardson, A.S. to LaNoue, G.S., Oct. 3, 1895 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Mayor's Office
  - ALS. Brashear, S.H. to Miller, I. Austin., Apr. 20, 1899 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - TLS. Brashear, S.H. to Miller, I. Austin., Apr. 29, 1899 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Executive Dept. ALS. Brashear, S.H. to Miller, I. Austin., Sept. 27, 1899 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - ALS. Brashear, S.H. to Miller, I. Austin., Jan. 12, 1900 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - ALS. Brashear, S.H. to Miller I. Austin., June 7, 1900 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - ALS. Brashear, S.H. to Miller, I. Austin., July 9, 1900 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - ALS. Brashear, S.H. to Miller, I. Austin., Sept. 27, 1900 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Brashear & Dannenbaum, Attorneys at Law. TLS. Brashear, S.H. to Miller, I. Austin., Dec. 28, 1900 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Other
  - Houston & Texas Central Railroad Company. TLS. Howe, M.G. to Miller, I. Austin., Feb. 21, 1900 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Texas World Publishing Company. Receipt., Mar. 25, 1897 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Westinghouse Electric & Manufacturing Company. TLS. Dusiuberre(?), Lemuel Baumister to LaNoue, G.M., May 17, 1894 (Box 1, Folder 18)